

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer/Software Engineer with an insatiable willingness to learn, who genuinely enjoys creating things and expressing my creative side developing ways to improve a user's experience on the web, one application at a time.

Employment

Pumpt, LLC Full Stack Developer Remote May 2020 to Current

Full Stack Developer role for a lean startup in the Recruitment sector, I am tasked with developing and maintaining their codebase, adding new features, database maintenance/backups/migrations, and completing tasks to ensure users are given the support they need.

Lambda School Remote Team Lead Aug. 2019 to May 2020

Internship position granted by Lambda School where Team Leads are tasked with engaging and leading a group of students varying in size from 6-10 in daily stand-ups, code review/assessment, taking attendance each day, acting as a resource to lean on when presented with a problem and helping to find the best path to a solution.

Stand and Stretch
Web Developer/Web Management Personnel
Apr. 2020 to Current

Freelance contractor position for a local web agency to complete various web management tasks, migrations and backups, also using my software engineering skills to assist with development of client e-commerce websites.

Projects

Travel Guard - Crime tracker and statistics map for travelers Oct. 2019 to Nov. 2019

Crime statistics application built on a MERN stack to generate and render current up-to-date crime statistics in areas that users intend to trravel to, with hot-maps and metrics pertaining to crime density per capita.

- Built out Authentication With AuthO and JWT.
- Used Mapboxes Geolocation API.
- Used Git & Github for version control on our app.
- Built out 100% of Application UI.
- Built a backend API using NodeJS, AWS, PostgreSQL

Contact

▼ richardsprins@gmail.com

www.richardsprins.me

458-209-7735

♥ Columbus, GA

Education

Lambda School

Apr. 2019 to Jan. 2020

Full Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp: Learned how to develop robust applications on the MERN stack

Skills

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

Python

SQL

React.JS

Node.JS

Redux

React Router

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

Express

MvSOL

BCrypt.JS

JWT

Firebase

SASS/SCSS

Diango

Flask

UI/UX

WordPress